（航海士）現在 敵影を見ず
No sign of the enemy at present.
Estimated time of arrival at the
Republican port town is nearly on schedule.
共和国港湾都市への到達は
ほぼ定刻どおりの見込み
After all this time, we're intervening.
（ドレイク）
今になっての本格介入…
The brass sure does lack patience.
上層部も こらえ性がない
They must be desperate to enjoy wine
and galettes at a Republican café.
Allied Kingdom Army Military Intelligence
Lieutenant Colonel Sir Isaac Dustin Drake
よほど
共和国のカフェで
ワインとガレットを
楽しみたいようだな
Don't you hate that only now, they send
us into a fire they could've put out?
（ジェフリー）今更 消火可能な
火事に飛び込まされるとは
たまったものではないですね
Well, the Imperial Army is nothing
if not based on rationalism.
まあ 帝国軍は合理主義の塊だ
The moment they realize they'll lose,
they'll probably sign a peace treaty.
敗北を悟れば あっさり講和条約に
サインする可能性もあるだろうが…
本当にいいんですか？
Are you sure about this?
I know you pulled some
strings via Intelligence, but...
いくら情報部で
手を回したとはいえ…
More than anyone, the colonel
understands the threat posed by the Empire.
大佐は誰よりも
帝国の脅威を知る兵士だ
He'll be a good fit for bull-baiting.
ブルバイティングには有用だろう
それに 救出以降―
Besides, ever since his rescue, he's been
at it, not even contacting his family.
家族にも連絡を取らず
ずっと あの調子だ
If no one stops him, he might
charge into enemy territory alone.
放っておけば
１人でも敵陣に飛び込みかねん
Squad 1 on the ground.
（ターニャ）こちら１班 降下完了
No hostile magical signatures.
現在 敵の魔導反応はなし
All squads, come in.
（ターニャ）
各班 応答せよ 各班…
All squads.
（ヴァイス）２班 降下完了
Squad 2 on the ground.
３班とのコンタクトも確立
敵の魔導反応はなし
We've established
contact with Squad 3.
No hostile magical signatures.
Squad 3 here.
（ケーニッヒ）こちら３班
同じく敵魔導反応なし
No hostile magical signatures.
Status of projectile from
the acceleration device?
（ターニャ）
追加加速装置の着弾成果は？
The door knocker appears to have hit
the main target quite precisely.
Republican Army Base, Point A
（ヴァイス）
ドアノッカーは―
重要拠点を ほぼ正確に
射抜いたもよう
Republican Army Base, Point B
We assume defensive teams at each
location are scrambling to respond.
防衛部隊は 各地点の
対応に追われているかと
Republican Army Base, Point C
Good.
よし 各位 魔導隠蔽(いんぺい)行軍での潜入と
破壊工作を開始
March with magical camouflage, and begin
infiltration and sabotage operation.
Remove equipment and respond swiftly.
装備を外し迅速に対応する
Squad 2, you're on target B.
２班はＢ目標 ３班はＣ目標
Squad 3, on target C.
We will take target A.
我々はＡ目標に当たる
With enemy reinforcements in mind,
敵援軍を考慮して
タイムリミットは10分だ
we have ten minutes to finish.
襲撃後は全速離脱せよ
After the attack, retreat at full speed.
Yes, ma'am.
All troops, move out!
（ターニャ）総員 突入だ！
Episode Ten
The Path to Victory
May 25, Unified Year 1925
Imperial Army High Council
Our army has moved the
（ゼートゥーア）現在の
戦況概要についてですが
我が軍はライン戦線右翼を
所定の防衛戦まで後退
Rhine Front's right flank back to
the designated defensive line.
大規模な戦線整理を
完了したところであります
We have completed a massive
reorganization of battle lines.
Why did we retreat so far?
（官僚）
なぜ そこまでの後退を？
下げすぎではないか？
Isn't this too much?
ああ その件につきましては
宮廷でも
About that... I've been notified that
the Imperial court has similar concerns.
同様の懸念をされていると
聞き及んでおります
宸襟(しんきん)を悩ますこと 小官も軍を
代表して おわびいたしますが―
On behalf of the military, I
apologize for worrying the emperor.
Unfortunately, as it is a
classified military matter,
誠に遺憾ながら詳細は
軍機につき ご容赦くださいませ
I can provide no further detail.
（財務官）では 財務省より１点
よろしいでしょうか
Then, may I make a comment
on behalf of the treasury?
（ゼートゥーア）どうぞ
Please.
As I'm sure we're all well aware,
（財務官）各位におかれては
ご存じかと思いますが―
most of the funding for this war
is through the sale of bonds.
既に戦費のほとんどを
内国起債で賄っている状況です
We have repeatedly
このような財政状況から
戦争の長期化は―
expressed concern that
prolonging this war may cause
看過しがたい経済問題を
誘発しかねないと―
considerable economic distress.
再三 警告させていただいて
おりましたが…
Regarding the topic you mention,
ご指摘の件につきましては
we very much appreciate everyone's
tremendous efforts and sacrifice.
銃後の皆様の重大な努力と犠牲に
大きく感謝するとともに―
喫緊の課題である
共和国軍撃滅に向け―
At the same time, we believe that
we are at a crucial stage that will lead
to the Republic's destruction.
鋭意 努める段階にあるかと
思う所存でございます
Any other casualties?
（共和国兵士）
他に負傷者はいるか？
Lieutenant...
（ターニャ）少尉
（ヴィーシャ）クリアです
We're clear.
No sign of optical camouflage.
（隊員）光学系偽装の反応はなし
Good.
（ターニャ）
よし 室内掃討戦を継続する
Proceed to clear the building.
It's only a matter of time before the
lowland's industrial area is lost.
（財務官）もはや
低地工業地帯の失陥は時間の問題
How do you respond to the fact that
西方工業地帯までもが
敵重砲の射程圏内に
the western industrial area is nearly
within range of enemy artillery?
捉えられつつある状況については
どう お考えなのでしょう？
At this rate,
（官僚）このままでは
我が国の工業生産力が
our country's industrial production
capabilities will be devastated.
壊滅的な状況に陥ります
We and the military must find a solution,
解決策を軍と協議できなければ―
不本意な政治的措置を
講じる必要もあると思われますが
or we may be forced to discuss
unpalatable political measures.
What does the military have
to say on that matter?
（外務官）
そうした事実理解についての
軍の存念は
いかがなものでしょうか？
（ゼートゥーア）
うん… うまいなあ
Delicious.
It appears this is an
abandoned facility, after all.
（ヴィーシャ）やはり
封鎖された施設のようですね
Damn.
（ターニャ）チッ 残り時間は？
（ヴィーシャ）およそ120
How much time left?
Roughly 120.
We have no choice.
やむをえん ハズレだろうと
軍令どおり焼き尽くす
We'll raze it per our orders,
even if it isn't the right site.
Prepare the explosion spell.
燃焼術式の用意だ！
Yes, ma'am.
（財務官）
産業基盤を失うのですぞ！
We're going to lose our
industrial foundation!
Why have you retreated so far that the
western industrial area is exposed?
（外務官）なぜ 西方工業地帯を
危機にさらすような戦線後退を？
This is obviously foolish!
明らかな愚行でしょう！
It's almost time.
（ルーデルドルフ）
そろそろ定刻か…
How do you plan to
take responsibility?
（外務官）
どう責任を取るつもりですか！
Give us a proper explanation.
（官僚）
納得のいく説明をしてください！
Do you not even
have an apology for us?!
（官僚）
わびの ひと言もないんですか！
01 to all units.
01より各位
目標Ａは敵司令部にあらず
Target A wasn't the
enemy headquarters.
各班 状況を報告せよ
All squads, report your situation.
All squads, report!
各班！ 状況報告だ！
What's the matter?
何をやっている！ 状況…
Report!
（ヴァイス）こちら02！
目標Ｂ アタリです
02 here.
Target B is a hit.
We destroyed their
communication headquarters.
通信司令部の破壊に成功！
（連絡兵）ハァ ハァ…
A-Apologies for
interrupting the meeting!
か… 会議中のところ 失礼します！
What was the code?
君 符号は？
We have a telegram.
入電！ “世界に冠たる
我らが祖国”であります！
"Our Fatherland, the ruler of the world."
I repeat.
繰り返します！
“世界に冠たる我らが祖国”
であります！
"Our Fatherland, the ruler of the world."
Acceptable, indeed...
実に結構！
03 here.
こちら03！ 同じく目標Ｃ…
Similarly, we've destroyed
an ammo depot at Target C.
弾薬庫を破壊しました
Good.
よし！ 各員 全速離脱して
友軍の潜水艦へ向かうぞ！
All units, retreat at full speed.
Head to our ally's submarine.
Our elite troops have destroyed the enemy
headquarters on the Rhine front.
先ほど 我が軍の精鋭部隊が
敵のライン方面軍 司令部を破壊
We've successfully destroyed the
enemy command structure.
指揮系統の撃滅に
成功いたしました
You've destroyed their headquarters?
（侯爵）総司令部を… 破壊？
As of now, Operation Shock
and Awe is complete.
（ゼートゥーア）現刻をもちまして
“衝撃と畏怖”作戦の完遂と―
I will now report on the third operation.
次なる第３作戦の開始を
ご報告させていただきます
I hope you look forward
to a follow-up report.
どうぞ
更なる続報をお待ちください
Rhine Theater: Republican Army  Left Wing, Rawl Lowlands
All units have arrived at the front lines.
（共和国兵士）
全部隊 進出予定線に到達！
Observation team reporting in.
（魔導師）
こちら観測班 我 敵影を見ず
No enemies in sight.
Enemy troops silent.
敵部隊に動きなし
Copy that.
（通信兵）
了解 司令部に指示を仰ぐ
Requesting orders from command.
What's your current situation?
（レルゲン）現在の状況は？
There are no problems.
（報告兵）はっ 問題ありません
The Republic's main forces have
arrived at the Rawl Lowlands.
共和国軍主力は ロール低地に到達
我が軍の右翼と対峙(たいじ)しています
They currently face our right flank.
What about the third operation?
（レルゲン）
第３作戦のほうは どうだ
I'm told it's ready.
既に 準備は万端とのこと
One year later, we finally have
a chance to pry open the door.
１年がかりで
ようやくドアを
こじあけられそうだな
Rhine Theater: Republican Army Right Wing, Mesienn Highlands
Man, it's so boring on this side...
（共和国兵士）
あ～あ… こっちは暇すぎだなあ
I envy the left flank.
（共和国兵士）
左翼の連中が羨ましいよ
Stop, don't do it.
おいっ やめとけ！
（共和国兵士）
ハッ どうせ撃ってこねえよ
They won't shoot at us, anyway.
Damn it.
まったく… いつまで
にらめっこをしてりゃいいんだ
When will this staring contest end?
Rhine Theater: Republican Army Right Wing Rear Echelon, Mesienn Highlands
Please respond.
（ビアント）応答願う
こちら ウイスキードッグ
This is Whiskey Dog.
Rhine Air Zone Control, please respond.
ライン空域管制 応答願う
電波妨害か？
Radio jamming?
Let's hurry.
（魔導師）とにかく急ぎましょう
The right flank will get so bored,
they'll start drinking industrial alcohol.
右翼の連中
このままじゃ暇すぎて
工業用アルコールにも
手を出しかねません
（ビアント）フッ…
伝令役も 意外と苦労が多いな
A messenger's life isn't easy.
んっ ついた…
There we go.
こ… これは 人為的な爆発
Was that a man-made explosion?
Operation Lock Pick
Destruction of Enemy Encampment
Is the Empire attacking?
帝国の攻撃… なのか？
Lieutenant Colonel, what just happened?
（魔導師）中佐殿！ 一体 何が…
E-Enemy troops advancing!
（魔導師）て… 敵影 視認！
It's a combined force of heavy armor,
along with mechanized infantry!
機甲部隊と機械化歩兵の
混成集団です！
くっ… 方面軍司令部に緊急！
Make an emergency call
to forward command!
戦略予備を ありったけ投じないと
穴が塞げなくなるぞ！
If they don't send proper reserves,
we can't shore up our defenses!
Make it fast! No time to spare!
急げ！ 一刻の猶予もない！
（魔導師）そ… それが
S-Sir...
I can't get through.
つながりません
What?
何？
I've been trying for a while,
（魔導師）先ほどから
試みていますが どの回線も―
but none of the frequencies are working!
全ての通信が
つながらないのです！
Don't tell me...
まさか…
Operation Lock Pick is a success.
解錠作戦 成功です！
Our forces' left flank has exited the
tunnels dug from our trenches.
（レルゲン）我が軍 左翼は―
塹壕(ざんごう)から掘り進めていた
トンネルによって地下を抜け―
They have set several mine fields
behind enemy encampments,
敵陣地下に多数の地雷を設置
坑道戦術により
防衛陣地および―
and with a coordinated
attack, they succeeded
in blasting the Republic's right flank away.
共和国軍右翼を
吹き飛ばしたとのこと
Open sesame, eh?
“開けゴマ”か…
I see your sense of
humor is still disastrous.
貴様は相変わらず
そういうセンスは壊滅的だな
A bit of wisdom from the
days before cannons.
（ルーデルドルフ）
大砲がない時代の英知だ
It's much better than being
weirdly pedantic.
変に衒学(げんがく)的より よほどいい
The Renaissance certainly wasn't bad,
（ゼートゥーア）
ルネサンスも悪くはないが―
but our concern should be the next
step, Operation Revolving Door.
重要なのは
続いての回転ドア作戦だ
How does it progress?
進捗状況は？
Without delay.
（レルゲン）滞りなく
The mixed force of heavy armor
and mechanized infantry,
解錠作戦によって
敵陣を破壊した機甲部隊と―
which broke through the enemy line
during Operation Lock Pick,
機械化歩兵の混成集団が
敵主力部隊の後方へ移動中
is proceeding to the enemy's main force.
可及的速やかに 敵主力の
全周包囲に向かっていると
Things are progressing, steadily and swiftly,
toward complete encirclement of the main force.
After this, they'll have to add a page
about us to books about the art of war.
（ゼートゥーア）
これで 戦争芸術の歴史に―
我々のページが追加されるな
Yes...
ああ この一撃…
この一撃で―
This one attack...
This one strike will end the war.
戦争は終わる！
What's going on out there?!
（共和国兵士）
戦況は どうなってるんだ！
隊長！ 隊長は無事か？
Where's the captain? Is he all right?!
What's with comms?
（共和国兵士）通信網は？
（共和国兵士）ダメです！
No good, sir!
I have orders from the commander!
（共和国兵士）
司令官は戦死しています！
The commander's dead!
（共和国兵士）どうなってんだ？
What the hell's happening?
What... What... is this?
な… 何なのだ これは…
This was... headquarters?
ここが… 司令部？
The Next Day, May 26 Imperial Territory
Good morning, Major!
少佐殿 おはようございます！
Good morning, gentlemen.
おはよう 諸君
I trust no idiot attempted
寝込みの
セレブリャコーフ少尉に―
いたずらを働くアホは
誰もいなかったかね？
any mischief on Lieutenant
Serebryakov while she slept?
No worries there.
ご安心ください いくら敵司令部の
破壊に浮かれていても
We may be excited about
destroying enemy command,
but we're still plenty anxious over our
submarine being potentially sunk.
回収先の潜水艦が沈んでは
たまりませんからね
Pardon me.
（乗組員）失礼します
（ノイマン）ん？
Message from Strategic HQ
Major Degurechaff.
（乗組員）デグレチャフ少佐殿
参謀本部より通達です
（ターニャ）ご苦労
Good work.
"Fantastic! Operation Lock Pick
was a success, then?
すばらしい！
解錠作戦が成功したのか
Which will get the Revolving
Door turning, as well."
これで回転ドアも
機能するというわけだ
（ターニャ）ん？ ああ 貴官らは
詳細を知らされてなかったな
Oh, I suppose you weren't
briefed on the details.
It's a top-secret plan that Strategic
HQ proposed to end the war.
参謀本部が進行中の
戦争終結に向けた極秘計画だ
The first operation
第１作戦 大規模後退による
敵主力部隊の誘引
was feigning a large-scale retreat
to lure the enemy's main force in.
The second operation
第２作戦 敵司令部を強襲しての
指揮系統撃滅
was the attack on enemy command
to disrupt their chain of command.
The third operation
第３作戦 坑道戦術による
敵陣地の突破
was the use of tactical tunneling
to break through the enemy line.
Bringing us to
そして
回転ドア作戦での敵主力包囲
Operation Revolving Door which will
surround the main enemy force.
Complete annihilation, using a
large-scale envelopment.
大規模包囲による完璧な撃滅
An example of the ideal
mobile encirclement.
これこそ まさに
機動包囲の理想形だ
Sounds like it's already been decided...
（グランツ）
つまり 趨勢(すうせい)は決したと？
Correct.
ああ 敵主力は袋のネズミだ！
The enemy's main forces
are now fish in a barrel.
ああっ… ンフフッ
（ヴィーシャ）やったー！
（隊員たち）おおー！
We did it!
All right!
Yes!
これより我々も本艦から出撃！
We will now deploy from the submarine.
包囲撃滅戦に参加したのち
帝都へ帰投する！
And after participating in
the encirclement attack,
we will return to the capital!
I'm sure you understand, but the field
trip doesn't end until you're home!
分かっているとは思うが
帰るまでが遠足だ！
勝利の宴に参加しないうちに
ヴァルハラへの抜け駆けは
No one can head to Valhalla without
joining the victory celebration!
許さんぞ！
Yes, ma'am!
Now! Fire!
（帝国兵士）今だ！ てーっ！
Retreat!
（共和国兵士）逃げろー！
（共和国兵士）何だ？
何がどうなっているんだ？
What is this?
What the hell's going on?!
My arm!
（共和国兵士）俺たちは
攻めていたんじゃなかったのか！
Weren't we on the offensive?
Hey!
おいっ！
Multiple casualties.
（将校）死傷者多数！
（将校）第３連隊は全滅！
The 3rd Regiment was wiped out!
Artillery units are down, too.
（将校）
歩兵部隊も壊滅状態です！
（指揮官）司令部の指示は？
Orders from command?
（通信兵）指揮系統は完全にマヒ！
矛盾する命令ばかりです！
Chain of command is totally paralyzed!
Nothing but contradictory orders!
後退だ！ 後退しろ！
Pull back! We need to retreat.
Pull back! The order is to retreat!
（共和国兵士）撤退！
（共和国兵士）撤退指示だー！
（共和国兵士）ひけー！
Pull back!
All Imperial forces engaged in the mission,
（通信兵）
作戦参加中の帝国軍部隊へ
offensive operation 177
is currently underway.
攻勢計画 第177号を発令中
All units, continue fighting.
総員 戦闘を継続せよ
This is Fairy 01.
（ターニャ）こちらフェアリー01
Confirming declaration of 177.
第177号の発令を了解
帝国に勝利を
Victory to the Empire.
さて諸君 我々の仕事は
帰還途中の捜索遊撃任務
Now, troops, our job is to find
and destroy any enemy
forces attempting to retreat.
All you have to do is attack
the enemy, if you find them.
敵を見つけたら
襲ってもよろしい程度の仕事だ
If the land forces'
performance is any indicator,
地上軍の働きぶりからして
出番は少ないだろう
you won't have much to do.
そういえば帝都では
我々の司令部襲撃をたたえ―
Back at the capital...
For our attack on enemy command,
ぜひ おごらせてくれというヤツが
軍団単位でいるそうだ
enough people to form an army
corps want to buy us drinks.
I can guarantee you'll have
free drinks for life.
タダ酒を一生分飲めると
保証しておくぞ
That's fantastic!
（隊員）最高だ！
（ターニャ）困ったことに
私はコーヒー党だがな
Which does me no good,
since I'm a coffee drinker.
The first large-scale
encirclement since Cannae...
（ターニャ）
カンネー以来の大規模包囲戦か
The Empire has created an unassailable,
golden monument in military history.
帝国軍は戦史に不滅の金字塔を
打ち立てたわけだ
Now that I think about it, being a
soldier who lives amidst combat
思えば 戦火に身を浸す
軍人という存在は―
can make you lose your mind, at times.
時として常識を失いがちだが―
But once there's peace again,
平和さえ戻ってくれば 全ては
日常によって置換されるはず
everyday life will restore everything!
So just a bit more...
だから もう少し…
もう少しの辛抱だ！
I need to be a little more patient.
With this attack... Just a bit more...
この一撃で あとわずかで…
戦争を終わらせられる！
the war will be over!
Rhine Control to all units.
（通信兵）
ラインコントロールより各隊
Multiple magical signatures
detected in area 42.
エリア42に複数の魔導反応
Look out for long-range
optical sniping spells.
長距離観測狙撃術式に警戒せよ
Area 42 is the patch of ocean near us...
エリア42というと…
近くの海上ですが
Rhine Control on general channels.
（通信兵）
ラインコントロールより一般通告
This message is for the
unidentified mage unit in area 42.
エリア42にて
識別を発しない魔導部隊へ
Identify yourselves immediately.
直ちに所属を明らかにせよ
繰り返す 所属を明らかにせよ
I repeat, identify yourselves.
（ターニャ）
こちらフェアリー大隊
This is Fairy Battalion.
What information is there on
this unidentified mage unit?
所属不明の
魔導部隊についての情報は？
No indicators of affiliation.
（通信兵）詳細は不明
だが 別地点の友軍からは―
But we've received
reports from allied forces
that they've had contact with
the Allied Kingdom's forces.
連合王国部隊との
交戦報告も入っている
The John Bulls are getting involved?
ジョンブルどもが介入したと？
I'm just part of operations,
so I can't confirm.
（通信兵）悪いが
一介の管制には判断しかねる
Copy that. We'll assume bogey is a bandit.
了解 ボギーをバンデットと推定す
よう撃の許可を！
Requesting permission to engage.
（通信兵）
直ちに警戒部隊を向かわせる
Sending a security echelon now.
You're to maintain your distance
and stand by until they arrive.
距離を保ったまま
到着まで待機せよ
Fairy 01, unable to comply! If we
can get the drop on them—
フェアリー01 承服できない！
先制でき… あっ！
グランツ！
Grantz!
（アンソン）１機 撃墜
One enemy down.
ンガッ ううん…
すさまじい寝相だな
This goes beyond tossing and turning...
（ヴィーシャ）う～ 爆裂術式…
Explosion spell...
何!?
セ… セレブリャコーフ少尉ど…
What?! L-Lieutenant Serebryakov—
大隊長～
目標を沈静化しましたあ
Captain, we've neutralized the target.
Captain, what are my next orders?
大隊長 次の指示を…
What the heck?
（グランツ）何だよ もう…
（ヴィーシャ）ンガッ…
Next Episode
Resistance